Agung Prakasya

email. aprksy@gmail.com; phone. +62 8-1975-1975-0; linkedIn. linkedin.com/in/agungprakasya/ github. github.com/aprksy

To: Hiring team at Level.io

Hi there, how are you today? Fine here. Let me first introduce myself, my name is *Agung Prakasya*, and I'm writing this letter to show you my interest in the position you're offering.

I'm currently working at *Quipper*, an ed-tech company, as a solution architect. I graduated from the Math dept. at *Bandung Institute of Technology* and have 15+ years of experience which hopefully —in this quickly evolving technology age— is still relevant.

I use Go and Linux standard tools in my last 6 years of work, mainly for concurrent data processing and microservices. I'm currently updating my C++ knowledge to 17/20 and learning Rust, V & Elixir. Before that, I used Delphi, C/C++, and a little bit of Python, PHP and Java. Please refer to my resume for more details, hopefully, you can find something of interest for your team.

I am interested to apply here because Level.io is a small team, and I think it's a good fit for me. And the advertisement also catching, it's specific and clear while staying humble. Aside from that, with the aforementioned technicalities I'm confident to be able to contribute to the team. I've been working with Win32 API for about 10 years. And for IPC, under Windows, I have worked with DCOM and OLE technology, while in Linux I used sockets, shared memory, and pipes, and used named pipes for both.

In my current job, one of my tasks is to implement a standard namely LTI 1.3 and translate it to workable items, pioneering the development process until it reached a stable state and handed over to the team. I'm sure I can catch up with the standard being used by the team and also would be happy to learn/share new things from/to the team.

I apologize for this lengthy email, but I hope you can understand. If you find something you would like to know more about, please don't hesitate to contact me. Thank you.

Sincerely,

Agung Prakasya

Agung Prakasya

email. aprksy@gmail.com; phone. +62 8-1975-1975-0;

linkedIn. linkedin.com/in/agungprakasya/

github. github.com/aprksy

personal info

education

Born: Ciamis, 20 May 1975 Live in East of Cibubur, West Java

Nationality: Indonesian

Degree in Math (2000) Math Dept. of Institut Teknologi Bandung Majoring in Computational Math Modelling

23 Years of total experience; 23+ years of coding in various languages; 17 years in various distributed systems; 8 years in biqdata and datastreams; 11 years of experience in energy and other industries —mostly on project management, solution architect & specialist position;

qualification

experience

Builds trusts, quides, inspiration wannabe Managed large multi-sites (Java, Sumatera, & leads team; Anticipates technology trends/change; Manages team of large size and/or high-skilled personnels; Mixes & matches personnels to achieve effective team composition; Polyglot coder (Go, C/C++, Delphi/Pascal, C#, etc); A long-time Linux/BSD cli-er; Very good on analysis and systematic problem solving, statistical data analysis and math modelling. Love to learn new things.

Kalimantan, Sulawesi & Bali) team of 150s persons, including developers, operators and managers for a 3 years managed service project; Managed a team of 3 exceptionally high skilled personnels for a nationwide project; Architected various systems: Industrial distributed system, SCADA-enterprise integration, bigdata migration, nationwide distributed biometric matching system, datastreams.

Programming & Development

Built for Productions:

- LTI 1.3 Core & Advantage Implementation; tags: Go
- Big Data; Text Processing; tags: Go, Linux Standard Tools, Awk
- Microservices; API Gateways; Dashboards; tags: Go, Node.js
- NIST format encoder/decoder; biometric image format validator; built a massive volume (terabytes) biometric image processing service. tags: Go C
- Android applications; Web applications; tags: Flutter, Node.js
- Industrial distributed system; Industrial

- data communication; Industrial software plugins; tags: C++, Delphi, OPC, Modbus
- Data visualization; Document/report generator; tags: D3.js, Ms.Office Automation, LATEX

Personal Research:

- Extended *Petrinet* library, for dynamic system modelling; **tags**: Go, V
- High Performance Toolset for Massive Text Data; tags: C++
- Elastic Ring data type for incomplete image congruence detection; tags: Algorithm, Datatype

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

QUIPPER EDUKASI INDONESIA (quipper.com)—Jakarta June 2022—Present Title: Solution Architect

Research & Design. Research & Design architecture for products, and propose transition phases to VPoE in adopting new architectures/technologies/approaches.

Adopting Standards. Perform pioneering on RFC and Standards implementation, consolidate requirements including timelines and convert to actionable items for used by development team.

Strategic Development. Perform strategic developments, by means of determine technology which will be use often, develop libraries and perform internal PoCs.

INFORMATIKA SOLUSI BISNIS (paques.id)—Jakarta February 2021—June 2022 Title: Senior Engineer Design solution architecture both for products and projects cust-mized for users.

- Q4.2021 Q2.2022. Architected Telkomsel Big Data Processing Solution Architect To provide a solution for data processing and analytics for communication data in Telkomsel. The solution to date, has been processing 50TB data per day and will grow to 90TB per day in Q1 2022.
- Q4.2021. Architected Solution for DSS Bursa Efek Indonesia Solution Architect
 To provide a solution for upgrading the DSS system of Bursa Efek Indonesia.
- Q2-Q3.2021. Architected Solution for Lab. Cyber–Kejagung

 Solution Architect

 To provide a solution for data processing and analytics for various data including reports, lawful intercepts, oneline news and social media.
- Q1.2021. Rearchitected Paques Media Intelligence engine

 Solution Architect
 To provide a more performant, flexible and bullet-proof internal engine for Paques
 Media Intelligence, including online-news crawler, NLP module and FTS services.

SIBERNETIK INTEGRA DATA (sibernetik.co.id)—Jakarta Dec 2017—Jan 2021 Title: Senior Engineer Determines company's technology related strategies Head of Solution Dev.

including technology roadmap, acquisition model, stacks, team skill sets requirements and partnerships.

- Q1.2020. Realtime core banking off-loading—BTPN Syariah Solution Architect
 To provide tools and mechanism to BTPN Syariah to perform realtime data off-loading
 from their T24 core banking system to surrounding application using Attunity and
 Kafka.
- Q4.2019. Information War Campaign—BSSN

 Technology Advisor
 To provide media monitoring tools to BSSN regarding issues in social and formal media.
 Functions: Sentiment analysis, bot detection, social media monitoring, etc.
- Q4.2019. Sistem Koordinasi Terpadu CAKRA–KOSTRAD Technology Advisor To provide media monitoring tools to KOSTRAD regarding issues in social and formal media, personnel distribution, war and peace strategies etc. Functions: Sentiment analysis, social media monitoring, etc.
- 2019–2020. Bigdata & Datastreaming Integration Technology Advisor
 —Commonwealth Bank

To provide Confluent Kafka data streaming solution to Commonwealth Bank Digital Banking. Functions: Realtime notification, realtime data ingestion, etc.

2019–2022. **Bigdata & Datastreaming Integration—BRI**Senior Solution Architect
To provide Confluent Kafka data streaming solution to BRI Digital Banking. Functions: Realtime notification, realtime data ingestion, fraud detection, cash management, etc.

Q3.2019. AIS live data streaming to Bigdata integration Technology Advisor —Ditjen Bea Cukai

To provide Confluent Kafka data streaming solution to Ditjen Beacukai. Functions: Realtime AIS data streaming from multiple sources, on the fly data query, on the fly data quality etc.

- Q1-Q3.2019. **Develop Marine Monitoring–MVP**Technology Advisor
 To build an MVP of B2B product, including determining data vendor, technology stack and developing team for building the product.
- Q1.2019. Operational Dashboard—BAKAMLA Technology Advisor To provide dashboard solution to BAKAMLA for their strategic and day-to-day operation. Functions: Realtime notification, organizer, maps etc.
- Q1.2019. Ceria Payment Gateway—BRI

 To implement in-merchant-app payment page and BRI side gateway for BRI ceria microloan.
- Q4.2018. Ceria Collection System—BRI

 To design & implement collection system for BRI Ceria, a microloan for online merchant's customers.
- Q4.2018. Ceria Merchant Dashboard–BRI

 To design & implement dashboard for BRI merchant (at the time this was written Tokopedia & Panorama)
- 2017–2018. Distributed Biometric Matching System Solution Architect, PM, Dev —Ditjen Imigrasi

To design & implement distributed biometric matching service for other subsystems in SIMKIM v.2 of Ditjen Imigrasi such as Izin Tinggal, Visa, Layanan Paspor, Cekal etc.

MEDIATRAC SISTEM KOMUNIKASI (dattabot.io)—Jakarta Aug—Dec 2017 Title: Senior Engineer To determine bigdata architecture and data migration methodology

Consultant

Q3-Q4.2017. **Bigdata migration—Bank Danamon** Sr. Solution Architect This project was to perform data migration from various data sources and core banking system to client's new data warehouse. This project employ various technologies such as Cloudera Hadoop, Talend, Sqoop etc.

5

DOWEDO-Jakarta

Sep 2016–Jan 2018

To design system architecture and implement Online Tourism eCommerce platform

Consultant

2016–2018. Building Tourism eCommerce Platform

Solution Architect

This project was to build tourism e-Commerce platform. However the life cycle was ended when it reached MVP.

TRIPATRA ENGINEERS & CONSTRUCTORS—Jakarta Nov 2013—Apr 2015

Title: Senior Engineer To ensure that project support systems keep aligned with all project

Sr. Engineer requirements despite characteristics difference between projects.

Q3.2014. Electronic Document Management System (EDMS) Project Manager —Internal project

This internal project objective was to develop a new major release of the system. The new release was the result of knowledge absorption from on going projects to keep the system aligned with future projects requirements.

Q2.2014. Issue Management System–Internal project Project Manager This internal project objective was to develop a system to manage projects issues. The main purpose of the system is, to track issue statuses, expedite for issue solutions and manage issue solution as lesson learned.

Q1.2014. Project Control Portal—Internal project

Project Manager
This internal project objective was to develop a centralized information service for the corporate on all projects project control. With this system, corporate are able to track progress status of the on going projects.

SINTESA SOLUSI UTAMA-Java, Kalimantan, Sumatera Feb 2006-Jun 2013 It was a self-owned company which was founded as information technology service provider.

2007–2013. Fuel Distribution Management System

Project Manager

(Java, Sumatera)–Elnusa Petrofin

This project was a managed service which provide IT service for client's whole fuel distribution operation, including IT systems, infrastructures and human resources.

Q3.2007. Interactive 3D simulation of Sidoarjo Mud Burst —Lapindo Brantas —Project Manager

The project was to build interactive 3D simulation of the Sidoarjo mud on Banjar Panji

site. This project used data provided by Lapindo Brantas to simulate the chronology of Sidoarjo mud burst and was to be presented by client to government and parliament.

Professional Service: Multi-remote Siemens WinCC integration Client: Perusahaan Gas Negara Aug 2011 OPC Specialist

The project was to integrate multi-stations Siemens Simatic WinCC which were distributed in different remote locations, South Sumatera and West Java using OPC communication standard.

Professional Service: WinCC-TOPServer Integration Feb 2007 Client: Yamatake Berca OPC Specialist

The project was to integrate Siemens Simatic WinCC and Yamatake TOPServer, using OPC communication standard for a Building Automation project.

Professional Service: SCADA–Enterprise Integration Feb–Sep 2006 Client: Kaltim Prima Coal OPC Specialist

The project was to integrate the existing Siemens Simatic WinCC and corporate information system (Mincom Minetrak –a mining management solution), which was currently in implementation phase. The project was using OPC communication standard to stream data from the SCADA system. The project was implemented in a live production system which did not tolerate shutdown.

SIEMENS INDONESIA-Jakarta, Balikpapan, Handil May 2004–Feb 2006 MRS-H251 Obsolete ESD and F&G System Revamping Control System Engineer

The project was Obsolete ESD and F&G System Revamping in a plant operated by Total E&P Indonesie - East Kalimantan. The objective is to revamp shutdown system which was handled by ALSPHA and implement Siemens technology for the function. The project was also to integrate the system being implement to the existing system which was Honeywell DCS.

It was a project with a distinctive level of difficulties and risks due to the involvment of a live production system and diverse technologies. This project employed various technologies such as OPC (OLE for Process Control), redundancy support, failsafe and others. End result of the individual work here was an OPC sub-system which bridging communication between Siemens Simatic WinCC and Honeywell APPNode which conform to both communication and safety standard.

SELF EMPLOYED-Jakarta

2000–Dec 2004

Running self-owned internet cafe & gaming center

Business Owner

with all around services such as printing services, photo-editing, banner & commercial design, billing system development, computer repair etc.

INTERESTS

coding, math, guitar & basses, woodworking, gardening